(Thank You, Doctor)
(شكرا يا دكتور)
(Adapted from Sheng Li's novel "ICU 48 Hours")
(مقتبس من رواية شنغ لي "ICU 48 Hours")
(Episode 24)
(الحلقة 24)
Mom.
أم.
The doctor made it very clear just now.
أوضح الطبيب الأمر للتو.
If Dad gets a nasogastric tube,
إذا حصل أبي على أنبوب أنفي معدي ،
he'll be able to live for another half a year.
سيتمكن من العيش لمدة نصف عام آخر.
Mom.
أم.
No matter what,
بغض النظر،
we don't want Dad to give up on treatment.
لا نريد أن يتخلى أبي عن العلاج.
I understand how you feel.
أنا أفهم شعورك.
That's your dad lying there.
هذا والدك يرقد هناك.
He's also my husband.
إنه أيضًا زوجي.
Of course I don't want him to leave us.
بالطبع لا أريده أن يتركنا.
I know all these years,
أعرف كل هذه السنوات ،
taking care of Dad has been hard on you.
كان الاعتناء بأبي صعبًا عليك.
Don't worry.
لا تقلق.
From now on, Xiao Jie and I...
من الآن فصاعدا ، شياو جي وأنا ...
will come back whenever we have time.
سوف أعود كلما كان لدينا الوقت.
We'll take good care of him together.
سنعتني به جيدًا معًا.
You know how many hospitals we've moved to.
أنت تعرف عدد المستشفيات التي انتقلنا إليها.
We've consulted so many specialists.
لقد استشرنا الكثير من المتخصصين.
They all said your dad's illness is irreversible.
قالوا جميعًا إن مرض والدك لا رجعة فيه.
You love your dad.
أنت تحب والدك.
You can't bear to part with him.
لا يمكنك تحمل الانفصال عنه.
But following what your elders want...
ولكن بعد ما يريده كبار السن ...
is also a part of filial piety.
هو أيضًا جزء من تقوى الأبناء.
At this point,
عند هذه النقطة،
why should we let him live and suffer?
لماذا نتركه يعيش ويتألم؟
Mom.
أم.
Why can't you put yourself in your dad's shoes?
لماذا لا تضع نفسك مكان والدك؟
Mom, it's not that we're not filial.
أمي ، ليس الأمر أننا لسنا أبناء.
It's not that we want to make Dad suffer.
ليس الأمر أننا نريد أن نجعل أبي يعاني.
If the doctor told me...
إذا قال لي الطبيب ...
that Dad can't hang in there anymore...
أن أبي لا يستطيع البقاء هناك بعد الآن ...
and that he can't be saved,
وأنه لا يمكن خلاصه ،
we would accept it.
سوف نقبله.
But he still has six months to live.
لكن لا يزال أمامه ستة أشهر ليعيشها.
What kind of six months would that be?
أي نوع من ستة أشهر سيكون ذلك؟
What kind of quality of life would he have?
أي نوع من نوعية الحياة سيكون لديه؟
Mom.
أم.
That's enough.
هذا يكفي.
Come with me.
تعال معي.
Let's go.
لنذهب.
Mom.
أم.
Why did you drag us back here?
لماذا جرتنا إلى هنا؟
What do you want to show us?
ماذا تريد ان ترينا؟
- Why is Dad's hand like this? - Be gentle.
- لماذا يد أبي هكذا؟  - كن لطيفآ.
What kind of hospital is this?
أي نوع من المستشفيات هذا؟
- I'm going to look for them. - Xiao Jie.
- سأبحث عنهم.  - شياو جي.
Keep it down. We're in a hospital.
احتفظ به.  نحن في المستشفى.
Have some manners.
تحلى ببعض الأخلاق.
The doctors have done everything they can.
لقد فعل الأطباء كل ما في وسعهم.
They really can't find...
هم حقا لا يجدون ...
any other place to give him injections.
أي مكان آخر لإعطائه الحقن.
Look at his ankle.
انظر إلى كاحله.
It's bandaged like this too.
ضمد مثل هذا أيضًا.
Over the past decade,
على مدى العقد الماضي،
your dad has been sick all the time.
والدك كان مريضا طوال الوقت.
He never stopped taking medicine or getting injections.
لم يتوقف عن تناول الأدوية أو الحقن.
That's why his body was overwhelmed long ago.
لهذا السبب كان جسده مغمورًا منذ فترة طويلة.
After he got Alzheimer's,
بعد إصابته بمرض الزهايمر ،
you didn't come home much,
لم تعد للمنزل كثيرا ،
so naturally, you also don't know much.
لذلك بطبيعة الحال ، أنت أيضًا لا تعرف الكثير.
You have no idea...
ليس لديك فكرة...
how much he has been suffering.
كم كان يعاني.
Your dad told me more than once...
قال لي والدك أكثر من مرة ...
that if he ever becomes terminally ill,
أنه إذا أصيب بمرض عضال ،
I must not listen to the doctors and save him.
يجب ألا أستمع إلى الأطباء وأنقذه.
The result of that...
نتيجة ذلك ...
would just be living a life without purpose.
سيعيشون حياة بدون هدف.
It's meaningless.
لا معنى له.
Look at his face.
انظر الى وجهه.
It's filled with pain.
إنها مليئة بالألم.
He had already lost the ability to speak...
لقد فقد بالفعل القدرة على الكلام ...
more than 600 days ago,
منذ أكثر من 600 يوم ،
but...
لكن...
I could hear him crying inside.
استطعت سماعه يبكي في الداخل.
"Set me free."
"حررنى."
Please, you two.
من فضلك ، أنتما الاثنان.
Don't let your dad suffer anymore.
لا تدع والدك يعاني بعد الآن.
Mom.
أم.
This...
هذه...
concerns my dad's life.
تتعلق بحياة والدي.
It's really hard for us to decide.
من الصعب حقًا أن نقرر.
Please give us some more time.
من فضلك امنحنا المزيد من الوقت.
We'll think about it.
التفكير جيدا حول هذا الموضوع.
I'm actually struggling inside too.
أنا في الواقع أكافح من الداخل أيضًا.
During this time,
خلال هذه المده،
I hope we can maintain basic treatment for him.
آمل أن نتمكن من الحفاظ على العلاج الأساسي له.
Okay?
تمام؟
Dad.
أب.
You've suffered a lot.
لقد عانيت كثيرا.
With Dad's condition like this,
مع حالة أبي كهذه ،
what should we do?
ماذا علينا ان نفعل؟
I don't know.
لا أعلم.
Let me think about it.
دعني افكر به.
Let me think about it some more.
اسمحوا لي أن أفكر في الأمر أكثر.
Dad. What are you doing here?
أب.  ما الذي تفعله هنا؟
Go to sleep.
اذهب إلى النوم.
I'm looking for something.
أنا أبحث عن شيء ما.
You're making so much noise here.
أنت تُحدث الكثير من الضجيج هنا.
I can't sleep.
لا أستطيع النوم.
For your birthday last year,
بمناسبة عيد ميلادك العام الماضي ،
I gave you a neck pillow.
أعطيتك وسادة للرقبة.
Where did you put it?
اين وضعتها؟
They're all in that bin.
كلهم في هذا الصندوق.
All the birthday presents you bought for me...
كل هدايا عيد الميلاد التي اشتريتها لي ...
are all in there.
كلها هناك.
Dad.
أب.
Why are you taking this?
لماذا تأخذ هذا؟
You never used this, right?
أنت لم تستخدم هذا أبدا ، أليس كذلك؟
That's right.
هذا صحيح.
You claimed that you especially bought it for me in Germany.
لقد زعمت أنك اشتريته خصيصًا لي في ألمانيا.
Do you think I don't know...
هل تعتقد أنني لا أعرف ...
that you just bought it for me at the airport...
التي اشتريتها لي للتو في المطار ...
for the sake of looking good?
من أجل المظهر الجيد؟
It was even several sizes too big.
كان حتى عدة أحجام كبيرة جدًا.
I couldn't use it at all.
لم أستطع استخدامه على الإطلاق.
That's why...
لهذا...
this is fate.
هذا هو القدر.
What fate?
ما مصير؟
You can't use it anyway. It's too big.
لا يمكنك استخدامه على أي حال.  انها كبيرة جدا.
I'll take it then.
سآخذها بعد ذلك.
Dad, it's my business whether I use it or not.
أبي ، هذا عملي سواء استخدمته أم لا.
You have to get my permission before taking it.
يجب أن تحصل على إذن مني قبل أخذها.
What are you talking about?
ما الذي تتحدث عنه؟
I bought this for you.
اشتريت هذا لك.
You gave it to me,
انت اعطيطها لي،
so it's mine now.
لذا فهو ملكي الآن.
Everything in this house is mine,
كل شيء في هذا المنزل لي ،
including you.
بما فيهم أنت.
Go to sleep now.
اذهب للنوم الأن.
Go to sleep.
اذهب إلى النوم.
My goodness.
رباه.
It was a gift.
وكانت هدية.
How can he take it back?
كيف يمكنه استعادتها؟
I did a follow-up ECG for the patient.
لقد أجريت متابعة لتخطيط القلب للمريض.
There's no typical myocardial ischemic change.
لا يوجد تغير إقفاري نموذجي لعضلة القلب.
The cardiac enzymes are also normal.
إنزيمات القلب طبيعية أيضًا.
I'm going to do another chest, abdomen, and artery CT scan on him.
سأقوم بعمل أشعة مقطعية أخرى على الصدر والبطن والشريان.
Where are you going?
إلى أين تذهب؟
What is it, Dr. Bai?
ما الأمر يا دكتور باي؟
Xiao Guang wanted me to give this to you.
شياو غوانغ أرادني أن أعطي هذا لك.
He wants to thank you for taking him to the amusement park.
يريد أن يشكرك على اصطحابه إلى مدينة الملاهي.
Xiao Guang?
شياو قوانغ؟
How did he know that I have a bad cervical spine?
كيف عرف أن لدي عمود فقري عنقي سيئ؟
That kid has been spending a lot of time with Xu Yi Ran lately.
كان هذا الطفل يقضي الكثير من الوقت مع Xu Yi Ran مؤخرًا.
Maybe Xu Yi Ran told him.
ربما أخبره Xu Yi Ran.
Try it. See if it fits.
جربها.  انظر إذا كان ذلك مناسبًا.
It fits perfectly.
تناسبها تماما.
Xiao Guang is quite thoughtful.
شياو قوانغ شديد التفكير.
Please thank him for me.
ارجوك اشكره علي
Sure.
بالتأكيد.
Okay, I'll get back to work.
حسنًا ، سأعود إلى العمل.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
What's with Dr. Bai?
ما مع دكتور باي؟
Who knows what's wrong with him?
من يدري ما خطبه؟
Dr. Xiao, let's go and eat.
دكتور شياو ، دعنا نذهب ونأكل.
Did you buy a neck pillow?
هل اشتريت وسادة للرقبة؟
Is it good?
هل هذا جيد؟
It's quite comfortable.
إنه مريح للغاية.
My neck has been sore lately.
كانت رقبتي مؤلمة في الآونة الأخيرة.
Where did you buy this? I want one too.
أين تشتري هذا؟  أريد واحد أيضا.
Xiao Guang gave it to me.
شياو غوانغ أعطاني إياه.
What a sweet boy.
يا له من فتى لطيف.
He's already so good with girls at such a young age.
إنه بالفعل جيد جدًا مع الفتيات في مثل هذه السن المبكرة.
Imagine how he'll be when he's grown up.
تخيل كيف سيكون عندما يكبر.
Why do I feel like...
لماذا أشعر بـ ...
this neck pillow probably isn't from Xiao Guang?
وسادة العنق هذه ربما ليست من شياو غوانغ؟
I think it's from Bai Zhu.
أعتقد أنه من باي تشو.
Why is that?
لماذا هذا؟
Think about it.
فكر في الأمر.
Xiao Guang is just a kid.
شياو غوانغ مجرد طفل.
How would he know that Dr. Xiao has a bad neck?
كيف يعرف أن رقبة دكتور شياو سيئة؟
Moreover,
علاوة على ذلك،
you also saw how excited Bai Zhu was just now.
لقد رأيت أيضًا كيف كان باي تشو متحمسًا الآن.
This neck pillow must be from him.
يجب أن تكون وسادة العنق هذه منه.
Yes.
نعم.
Dr. Bai was indeed very excited just now.
كان الدكتور باي متحمسًا جدًا للتو.
But why did Dr. Bai give Dr. Xiao a neck pillow?
لكن لماذا أعطى الدكتور باي وسادة الرقبة للدكتور شياو؟
I'm going to make my rounds.
سأقوم بجولاتي.
You're not going to eat?
أنت لن تأكل؟
We'll go then.
سنذهب بعد ذلك.
Ms. Lin.
السيدة لين.
I made pear soup with white fungus.
لقد صنعت حساء الكمثرى بالفطر الأبيض.
Have some while it's hot.
تناول البعض بينما يكون الجو حارًا.
I have no appetite.
ليس لدي أي شهية.
You look terrible.
تبدو فظيعا.
Why don't you go home and get some rest?
لماذا لا تذهب للمنزل وتحصل على قسط من الراحة؟
No.
رقم.
Shi Lei needs me.
شي لي يحتاجني.
You can't do this to yourself.
لا يمكنك أن تفعل هذا بنفسك.
Watch him for me.
احترس من أجلي.
I'm going to the restroom.
انا ذاهب الى الحمام.
What's wrong?
ما هو الخطأ؟
Are you okay?
هل انت بخير؟
I'm fine. I just feel a little dizzy.
أنا بخير.  أنا فقط أشعر بقليل من الدوار.
Let me help you up.
دعني اساعدك
I'll take a look at you.
سوف ألقي نظرة عليك.
You're just too tired.
أنت متعب للغاية.
We're giving you some glucose.
نعطيك بعض الجلوكوز.
You'll be fine after some rest.
ستكون بخير بعد قسط من الراحة.
Dr. Xiao.
دكتور شياو.
Have a seat.
تفضل بالجلوس.
It has been a long time since I saw Shi Lei smile at me.
لقد مر وقت طويل منذ أن رأيت شي لي يبتسم في وجهي.
We've been together for 40 years.
لقد كنا معًا لمدة 40 عامًا.
In these 40 years,
في هذه السنوات الأربعين ،
we've given to each other...
قدمنا ​​لبعضنا البعض ...
and protected each other.
ويحمي كل منهما الآخر.
We've always given each other our warmest smiles.
نحن دائما نعطي بعضنا البعض أحر ابتساماتنا.
We always shared even the bits and pieces...
لقد شاركنا دائمًا حتى الأجزاء والقطع ...
of our work and lives.
من عملنا وحياتنا.
We had endless topics to talk about.
كان لدينا مواضيع لا نهاية لها للحديث عنها.
Even if there were occasionally some small frustrations,
حتى لو كان هناك أحيانًا بعض الإحباطات الصغيرة ،
they garnished our lives.
لقد زينوا حياتنا.
Were we too lavish before...
هل كنا فخورين جدا من قبل ...
and used up all of our happiness?
واستنفدت كل سعادتنا؟
I wonder if their children have made up their minds.
أتساءل عما إذا كان أطفالهم قد اتخذوا قرارهم.
What is there to think about?
ما الذي يوجد للتفكير فيه؟
They're disrespecting their elders' wishes.
إنهم لا يحترمون رغبات شيوخهم.
How is that disrespect?
كيف يتم هذا عدم الاحترام؟
I think they're disrespecting life.
أعتقد أنهم لا يحترمون الحياة.
You have no idea.
ليس لديك فكرة.
Lin Ruo Yu and Li Shi Lei's love story...
قصة حب لين رو يو ولي شي لي.
is as romantic as a TV drama.
هي رومانسية مثل الدراما التلفزيونية.
The scene back then...
المشهد في ذلك الوقت ...
is etched in my mind forever.
محفور في ذهني إلى الأبد.
Shi Lei and I...
شي لي وأنا ...
met in an accident.
التقى في حادث.
It was an unexpected fate.
لقد كان مصيرًا غير متوقع.
I traveled to Shanghai on my own,
سافرت إلى شنغهاي بمفردي ،
but I got acute appendicitis.
لكنني أصبت بالتهاب الزائدة الدودية الحاد.
Shi Lei was my attending physician.
كان شي لي الطبيب المعالج.
I didn't know anyone here.
لم أكن أعرف أحداً هنا.
I was filled with fear and worry.
كنت مليئا بالخوف والقلق.
The first time I met Shi Lei,
في المرة الأولى التي قابلت فيها شي لي ،
it felt like...
هذا شعور رائع...
I had known him for a long time.
كنت أعرفه لفترة طويلة.
As a doctor,
كطبيب،
his professionalism, sense of responsibility,
احترافه ، حس المسؤولية ،
patience, and thoughtfulness...
الصبر والتفكير ...
was the light...
كان الضوء ...
that saved me from danger...
أنقذني من الخطر ...
when I fell into an abyss.
عندما سقطت في الهاوية.
Later on, we talked a lot.
في وقت لاحق ، تحدثنا كثيرا.
The more we talked,
كلما تحدثنا أكثر ،
we felt like we were soulmates.
شعرنا وكأننا رفقاء الروح.
He can read my mind.
يمكنه قراءة رأيي.
He's the one who understands me the most.
إنه أكثر من يفهمني.
She's kidnapping him in the name of love.
إنها تختطفه باسم الحب.
Why are you so worked up?
لماذا أنت مشغول جدا؟
No wonder she's always talking...
لا عجب أنها تتحدث دائما ...
about the wind, earth, sky, clouds, rain, and stuff.
عن الرياح والأرض والسماء والسحب والمطر والأشياء.
That's a sign that she's closing herself off.
هذه علامة على أنها تغلق نفسها.
She is too immersed in her own world.
هي منغمسة جدا في عالمها الخاص.
Then what happened?
ثم ماذا حدث؟
It was just a one-chance encounter.
لقد كانت مجرد فرصة واحدة.
They couldn't wait to get married right after that?
لا يمكنهم الانتظار حتى يتزوجوا بعد ذلك مباشرة؟
You don't even know what love is.
أنت لا تعرف حتى ما هو الحب.
Her relationship with Li Shi Lei is true love.
علاقتها مع Li Shi Lei هي حب حقيقي.
- I don't believe that. - I believe it.
- لا أصدق ذلك.  - اصدق ذلك.
Anyway, after that,
على أي حال ، بعد ذلك ،
Lin Ruo Yun came to Shanghai.
جاء لين رو يون إلى شنغهاي.
With his own ability and experience,
مع قدرته وخبرته الخاصة ،
Li Shi Lei became an excellent internal medicine doctor.
أصبح لي شي لي طبيبة ممتازة في الطب الباطني.
As the two of them admired,
كما أعجب الاثنان ،
respected, and relied on each other,
محترمين ، ومعتمدين على بعضنا البعض ،
their love deepened.
تعمق حبهم.
Later on, you know that Li Shi Lei got pneumonia.
لاحقًا ، تعلم أن لي شي لي أصيب بالتهاب رئوي.
His children were busy with work.
كان أطفاله مشغولين بالعمل.
Lin Ruo Yun took care of him every day.
اعتنى به لين رو يون كل يوم.
She fed him medicine and changed his dressing every day.
كانت تطعمه الدواء وتغير ضماداته كل يوم.
Lin Ruo Yun found it increasingly hard...
وجد لين رو يون الأمر صعبًا بشكل متزايد ...
to be apart from him.
ليكون بعيدا عنه.
She felt he was so precious.
شعرت أنه كان ثمينًا جدًا.
Ever since we met,
منذ أن التقينا ،
Shi Lei has put all of his heart into taking care of me.
لقد وضع شي لي كل قلبه في الاعتناء بي.
He protected me from all obstacles...
لقد حماني من كل العوائق ...
and gave me his all.
وأعطاني كل ما لديه.
I remembered it all...
تذكرت كل شيء ...
and kept it in my heart.
واحتفظت به في قلبي.
Even though we went on to have two kids...
على الرغم من أن لدينا طفلين ...
and no longer had time to ourselves,
ولم يعد لدينا وقت لأنفسنا ،
we still loved each other just the same.
ما زلنا نحب بعضنا البعض بنفس الطريقة.
They had their eldest son Li Song...
كان لديهم ابنهم الأكبر لي سونغ ...
in the second year of their marriage.
في السنة الثانية من زواجهما.
They had their youngest daughter in the fourth year.
أنجبا ابنتهما الصغرى في السنة الرابعة.
Her name is Li Jie.
اسمها لي جي.
Although they have children,
على الرغم من أن لديهم أطفال ،
they maintained a romance...
لقد حافظوا على الرومانسية ...
like one out of a fairy tale.
كواحد من القصص الخيالية.
Lin Ruo Yun advocates the concept of Western education,
يؤيد لين رو يون مفهوم التعليم الغربي ،
so she lets her kids run free and be independent.
لذا فهي تسمح لأطفالها بالركض بحرية والاستقلال.
She's a teacher herself,
هي نفسها معلمة ،
so she had summer and winter vacations every year.
لذلك كانت لديها إجازة صيفية وشتوية كل عام.
So every year,
لذلك كل عام ،
she would travel with her husband twice.
كانت تسافر مع زوجها مرتين.
Her exact words were,
كانت كلماتها بالضبط ،
"We have to walk through..."
"علينا أن نمشي من خلال ..."
"every corner of the world while we're still young."
"كل ركن من أركان العالم ونحن ما زلنا صغارًا."
Shi Lei liked to give me flowers.
أحب شي لي أن يعطيني الزهور.
Every year on my birthday,
كل عام في عيد ميلادي ،
I would get fresh flowers...
سأحصل على زهور نضرة ...
that he would choose especially for me.
أنه سيختار خاصة بالنسبة لي.
There were hundreds of them.
هناك المئات منهم.
Blooming red roses...
تتفتح الورود الحمراء ...
would fill the entire house.
سوف تملأ المنزل بأكمله.
On the other hand, he often forgot...
من ناحية أخرى ، غالبًا ما نسي ...
the kids' birthdays.
أعياد ميلاد الأطفال.
He also liked to take me on trips.
كان يحب أيضًا اصطحابي في رحلات.
We took a walk...
أخذنا جولة مشيا...
on Golden Beach in Australia.
على جولدن بيتش في أستراليا.
We saw the snow in Hokkaido together.
رأينا الثلج في هوكايدو معًا.
We admired the wildflowers on the roads together,
لقد أعجبنا بالأزهار البرية على الطرق معًا ،
the fresh green leaves on the trees,
الأوراق الخضراء الطازجة على الأشجار ،
the flowing water,
المياه المتدفقة ،
the vast land,
الأرض الشاسعة ،
and the sunset on the horizon.
وغروب الشمس في الأفق.
Life is finite,
الحياة محدودة
so we really cherished each other.
لذلك كنا نعتز ببعضنا البعض حقًا.
We seldom fought...
نادرا ما قاتلنا ...
and rarely separated.
ونادرا ما ينفصلون.
Over the past 40 years,
على مدار الأربعين عامًا الماضية ،
our love for each other has grown stronger.
نما حبنا لبعضنا البعض أقوى.
It never changed with time.
لم يتغير مع مرور الوقت.
But now,
لكن الآن،
the one who understands me the most...
من يفهمني أكثر ...
is slipping further away from me day by day.
يبتعد عني يومًا بعد يوم.
He's leaving me by forgetting me.
إنه يتركني بنسياني.
Dr. Xiao.
دكتور شياو.
Do you also think...
هل تعتقد ايضا ...
I'm a heartless woman?
انا امراة بلا قلب؟
I can tell...
استطيع أن أقول...
that you really love him.
أنك تحبه حقًا.
Thank you, Dr. Xiao.
شكرا لك دكتور شياو.
Thank you for listening to me.
شكرا لاصغائك.
Get some rest.
خذ قسطا من الراحة.
Unfortunately,
للأسف،
no matter how romantic and beautiful a relationship is,
مهما كانت العلاقة رومانسية وجميلة ،
you still have to face the torture of death.
لا يزال يتعين عليك مواجهة عذاب الموت.
It's someone else's love story.
إنها قصة حب شخص آخر.
How do you know it so well?
كيف تعرفه جيدا؟
Are you his family?
هل انتم عائلته
Lin Ruo Lin shared...
شارك Lin Ruo Lin ...
their love story online.
قصة حبهم على الإنترنت.
I accidentally saw it...
رأيته بالصدفة ...
when I was on the Internet.
عندما كنت على الإنترنت.
Accidentally?
بالصدفة؟
I think it was intentional.
أعتقد أنه كان متعمدا.
Ms. Jiang.
السيدة جيانغ.
Are you criticizing me again?
هل تنتقدني مرة أخرى؟
We're nurses,
نحن ممرضات ،
not a gossip magazine.
ليست مجلة ثرثرة.
Tell me.
أخبرني.
Is talking about our patients' privacy...
يتحدث عن خصوصية مرضانا ...
an appropriate thing to do?
شيء مناسب لتفعله؟
No.
رقم.
Have you forgotten the lesson you got last time?
هل نسيت الدرس الذي حصلت عليه آخر مرة؟
No, I didn't.
لا ، لم أفعل.
Poor thing, hurry and eat.
مسكين ، اسرع وكل.
Remember it.
تذكر ذلك.
Mom.
أم.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
We're inserting a nasogastric tube into him.
نحن ندخل أنبوب أنفي معدي بداخله.
Mom.
أم.
About Dad's condition, we've already decided.
حول حالة أبي ، لقد قررنا بالفعل.
I don't agree.
أنا لا أوافق.
Dr. Tang.
دكتور.  تانغ.
I'm Li Shi Lei's attending physician.
أنا لي شي لي الطبيب المعالج.
You should have told me...
كان عليك أن تخبرني...
that some of his family members...
أن بعض أفراد عائلته ...
requested for nasogastric intubation.
طلب للتنبيب الأنفي المعدي.
You acted on your own.
لقد تصرفت بمفردك.
Who will take responsibility if something goes wrong?
من سيتحمل المسؤولية إذا حدث خطأ ما؟
But they're the patient's children.
لكنهم أبناء المريض.
The patient's wife didn't agree to it.
زوجة المريض لم توافق على ذلك.
The family hasn't come to a consensus.
لم تتوصل العائلة إلى توافق.
As doctors, how can we decide this on our own?
كأطباء ، كيف يمكننا أن نقرر هذا بأنفسنا؟
Dr. Tang.
دكتور.  تانغ.
We should separate our likes and dislikes...
يجب أن نفصل بين إبداءات الإعجاب وعدم الإعجاب ...
from our profession as a doctor.
من مهنتنا كطبيب.
Dr. Xiao.
دكتور شياو.
It's my mistake.
انه خطأي.
What should we do now?
ماذا يجب أن نفعل الآن؟
Let's wait for the family's decision.
دعنا ننتظر قرار الأسرة.
You've been together for decades.
لقد كنتما معًا منذ عقود.
You know him very well.
أنت تعرفه جيدًا.
My dad has never been one to give up so easily.
لم يكن والدي أبدًا من يستسلم بهذه السهولة.
Whether it's his work or his health,
سواء كان عمله أو صحته ،
as long as there's still hope for him,
طالما لا يزال هناك أمل له ،
he won't give up.
لن يستسلم.
We also visited many doctors in the past two days.
كما قمنا بزيارة العديد من الأطباء في اليومين الماضيين.
That's how we came to this decision.
هكذا توصلنا إلى هذا القرار.
So your decision...
لذا قرارك ...
is to torture him with these cold tubes?
هل تعذبه بهذه الأنابيب الباردة؟
Mom.
أم.
I don't think our disagreement...
لا أعتقد أن خلافنا ...
lies in whether Dad should be intubated or not.
يكمن في ما إذا كان يجب تنبيب أبي أم لا.
It's about...
يتعلق الأمر ...
whether it's worth it for him to keep living.
سواء كان الأمر يستحق أن يستمر في العيش.
How will he keep living?
كيف سيستمر في العيش؟
What kind of quality of life will he have?
ما نوع نوعية الحياة التي سيحصل عليها؟
Didn't the doctor already tell you?
ألم يخبرك الطبيب بالفعل؟
Most of his brain tissue is already dead.
معظم أنسجة دماغه ماتت بالفعل.
His heart and lungs are starting to fail.
بدأ قلبه ورئتيه بالفشل.
That means his life has reached its final stages.
هذا يعني أن حياته وصلت إلى مراحلها النهائية.
We're educated people.
نحن أناس مثقفون.
Can't you respect science?
ألا يمكنك احترام العلم؟
Didn't the doctor also say...
ألم يقل الطبيب أيضا ...
that he still has half a year to live?
أنه لا يزال أمامه نصف عام ليعيش؟
Never mind half a year,
لا تهتم بنصف عام ،
but even if Dad is leaving us tomorrow,
لكن حتى لو رحل أبي غدًا ،
we have to get through today with him.
علينا أن نجتاز اليوم معه.
We absolutely won't give up.
نحن على الاطلاق لن نستسلم.
I won't give up either.
لن أستسلم أيضًا.
Mom.
أم.
It has been hard on you to take care of Dad all these years.
لقد كان من الصعب عليك رعاية أبي كل هذه السنوات.
From now on,
من الان فصاعدا،
Xiao Jie and I will take care of him.
شياو جي وأنا سوف نعتني به.
Go home and get some rest.
اذهب للمنزل واحصل على قسط من الراحة.
I'm really sorry.
أنا حقا آسف.
If your family cannot come to a consensus,
إذا لم تتمكن عائلتك من التوصل إلى توافق ،
I can't insert a nasogastric tube in the patient.
لا يمكنني إدخال أنبوب أنفي معدي في المريض.
Please understand.
من فضلك إفهم.
Okay then.
حسنا إذا.
I'll contact another hospital.
سأتصل بمستشفى آخر.
I hope you can cooperate and let us transfer hospitals.
أتمنى أن تتعاون وتسمح لنا بنقل المستشفيات.
As a doctor,
كطبيب،
I don't recommend transferring the patient now.
لا أوصي بنقل المريض الآن.
The patient is very weak.
المريض ضعيف جدا.
His life will be in danger if anything goes wrong.
ستكون حياته في خطر إذا حدث خطأ ما.
If you think I'm trying to scare you...
إذا كنت تعتقد أنني أحاول إخافتك ...
and you don't trust me,
وأنت لا تثق بي ،
you can go to another hospital...
يمكنك الذهاب إلى مستشفى آخر ...
to consult another doctor.
لاستشارة طبيب آخر.
Dr. Xiao.
دكتور شياو.
Do you also think the same as my mom?
هل تعتقد أيضا نفس أمي؟
Do you think we're torturing my dad?
هل تعتقد أننا نعذب والدي؟
In my opinion, neither you nor Ms. Lin...
في رأيي ، لا أنت ولا السيدة لين ...
is right or wrong.
صواب أم خطأ.
Your ways of love are just different.
طرق الحب الخاصة بك فقط مختلفة.
As for whether a nasogastric tube should be given to the patient,
أما فيما يتعلق بإعطاء المريض أنبوب أنفي معدي ،
your family should discuss it again.
يجب على عائلتك مناقشتها مرة أخرى.
I will respect your decision.
سأحترم قرارك.
I'll get back to work then.
سأعود إلى العمل بعد ذلك.
So? What did she say?
لذا؟  ماذا قالت؟
Li Song.
لي سونغ.
Let's find another hospital for Dad.
لنجد مستشفى آخر لأبي.
Hello, Dr. Zhang.
مرحبا دكتور تشانغ.
This is Li Song.
هذه لي سونغ.
I'd like to consult you about my dad's condition again.
أود استشارتك بشأن حالة والدي مرة أخرى.
Hello.
مرحبًا.
Dr. Xiao.
دكتور شياو.
This is Lin Ruo Yun.
هذا لين رو يون.
I'd like to meet you.
أود أن ألتقي بكم.
I'm sorry about the nasogastric intubation.
أنا آسف بشأن التنبيب الأنفي المعدي.
It's not your fault.
انها ليست غلطتك.
I just didn't expect...
أنا فقط لم أتوقع ...
he would suffer so much...
سيعاني كثيرا ...
in the last moments of his life.
في اللحظات الأخيرة من حياته.
I'm also helpless in the face of all of this.
أنا أيضًا عاجز عن مواجهة كل هذا.
That's what pains me the most.
هذا هو أكثر ما يؤلمني.
I understand.
أفهم.
To your family,
لاهلك،
the patient leaving you...
المريض يتركك ...
is an unbearable pain in your lives.
هو ألم لا يطاق في حياتك.
They've just made a different choice than you.
لقد اتخذوا للتو خيارًا مختلفًا عنك.
So don't blame yourself.
لذلك لا تلوم نفسك.
I know.
أنا أعرف.
Neither of our ideas is right or wrong.
لم تكن أي من أفكارنا صحيحة أو خاطئة.
They want Shi Lei to live.
يريدون شي لي أن يعيش.
I don't want him to be stuck in a living nightmare.
لا أريده أن يكون عالقًا في كابوس حي.
I also promised Shi Lei...
كما وعدت شي لي ...
that I wouldn't let him suffer in the last moments of his life.
لن أتركه يعاني في اللحظات الأخيرة من حياته.
For Shi Lei,
لشي لي ،
I must be brave.
يجب أن أكون شجاعا.
I must persevere.
لا بد لي من المثابرة.
Dr. Xiao.
دكتور شياو.
If you or your hospital...
إذا كنت أنت أو المستشفى الخاص بك ...
is affected throughout all of this,
يتأثر خلال كل هذا ،
I'll apologize to you in advance now.
سأعتذر لك مقدما الآن.
Dr. Song and Dr. Zhang said the same thing.
قال الدكتور سونغ والدكتور تشانغ نفس الشيء.
They don't recommend letting Dad leave the hospital.
لا يوصون بالسماح لأبي بمغادرة المستشفى.
Li Song, look.
لي سونغ ، انظر.
What is it?
ما هذا؟
Stop taking photos.
توقف عن التقاط الصور.
- Be quiet. - Be quiet for a while.
- كن هادئاً.  - كوني هادئة لبعض الوقت.
- Be quiet for a moment. - If you have any questions,
- كن هادئا للحظة.  - إذا كان لديك أية أسئلة،
you can go to our hospital's communication room.
يمكنك الذهاب إلى غرفة الاتصالات بالمستشفى.
They'll answer your questions there.
سوف يجيبون على أسئلتك هناك.
- Everybody, be quiet. - Please be quiet.
- الجميع ، كوني هادئة.  - الرجاء الهدوء.
Be quiet, okay?
كن هادئا ، حسنا؟
- We can't answer you right now. - What's going on?
- لا يمكننا الرد عليك الآن.  - ماذا يحدث هنا؟
Lin Ruo Yun went to the media and accused her son and daughter...
ذهبت لين رو يون إلى وسائل الإعلام واتهمت ابنها وابنتها ...
of torturing Li Shi Lei.
من تعذيب لي شي لي.
It's a trending topic now.
إنه موضوع شائع الآن.
She's stirring up the public.
إنها تثير الرأي العام.
You're affecting our patients, okay?
أنت تؤثر على مرضانا ، حسنًا؟
We can't work with you here.
لا يمكننا العمل معك هنا.
Regarding the decision...
بخصوص القرار ...
of whether to insert the nasogastric tube or not,
سواء لإدخال الأنبوب الأنفي المعدي أم لا ،
you handled it well.
تعاملت معها بشكل جيد.
A doctor shouldn't get involved in the family's disputes.
لا ينبغي للطبيب أن يتورط في نزاعات الأسرة.
You can only guide them toward a solution.
يمكنك فقط إرشادهم نحو الحل.
Whether the family chooses curative care...
ما إذا كانت الأسرة تختار الرعاية العلاجية ...
or to let things go with the flow,
أو ترك الأمور تسير مع التيار ،
we are in no place to criticize them.
لسنا في مكان ننتقدهم فيه.
As doctors,
كأطباء ،
we must respect the opinions of our patients...
يجب أن نحترم آراء مرضانا ...
and their families...
وعائلاتهم ...
and give them all the help they need.
ومنحهم كل المساعدة التي يحتاجون إليها.
A lot of times,
في الكثير من الأحيان،
a person's journey to death...
رحلة الإنسان إلى الموت ...
is very long and painful.
طويلة جدا ومؤلمة.
But the family's opinion...
لكن رأي العائلة ...
is to save them if we can.
هو إنقاذهم إذا استطعنا.
So in a way,
بطريقة ما ،
this kind of behavior...
هذا النوع من السلوك ...
actually prolongs the patient's suffering.
في الواقع يطيل من معاناة المريض.
Sometimes, it's really hard to make a decision.
في بعض الأحيان ، من الصعب حقًا اتخاذ قرار.
Life's biggest frustration...
أكبر إحباط في الحياة ...
is not being able to choose life and death.
عدم القدرة على اختيار الحياة والموت.
If the patient's family...
إذا كانت أسرة المريض ...
still cannot come to an agreement after some time,
لا يزال لا يمكن التوصل إلى اتفاق بعد مرور بعض الوقت ،
I'll talk to them.
سأتحدث معهم.
Does that sound good?
هل هذا الصوت جيدة؟
Don't let this get in the way of your work.
لا تدع هذا يعيق عملك.
Go on.
تابع.
Mom.
أم.
You want to keep the promise you made to Dad.
تريد أن تفي بالوعد الذي قطعته لأبي.
We understand that.
نحن نفهم ذلك.
You want to reminisce about the love you had with Dad.
تريد أن تتذكر الحب الذي حظيت به مع أبي.
We have no objection to that.
ليس لدينا اعتراض على ذلك.
What we can't accept...
ما لا يمكننا قبوله ...
is you exposing our family's private matters online.
هل تقوم بكشف الأمور الخاصة لعائلتنا عبر الإنترنت.
When I see those netizens, who don't even know the truth,
عندما أرى مستخدمي الإنترنت الذين لا يعرفون الحقيقة ،
continuously liking, sharing our story,
باستمرار الإعجاب ، مشاركة قصتنا ،
and criticizing us,
وانتقادنا ،
it feels like they're telling us,
يبدو الأمر وكأنهم يخبروننا ،
"Why don't you let your dad hurry up and die?"
"لماذا لا تدع والدك يسرع ويموت؟"
"You're making your parents suffer like this."
"أنت تجعل والديك يعانيان هكذا".
I find it so ridiculous. Do you understand that?
أجده سخيفا جدا  هل تفهم ذلك؟
They're not talking about anyone else.
إنهم لا يتحدثون عن أي شخص آخر.
They're talking about our dad.
إنهم يتحدثون عن والدنا.
Mom.
أم.
You exposed our family matters to the public...
لقد كشفت عن أمور عائلتنا للجمهور ...
and let them judge us.
ودعهم يحكمون علينا.
Is this what you call love?
هل هذا ما تسميه حب؟
Mom.
أم.
You worked hard to take care of Dad.
لقد عملت بجد لرعاية أبي.
We acknowledge that.
نحن نعترف بذلك.
Xiao Jie and I also ran around and wore ourselves out...
ركضت أنا وشياو جي حولنا وأرهقنا أنفسنا ...
for Dad's health.
من أجل صحة أبي.
Your love is a child's love for his parents.
حبك هو حب الطفل لوالديه.
What we have is romantic love.
ما لدينا هو الحب الرومانسي.
It's different.
انها مختلفه.
So we just have to watch Dad die?
إذن علينا فقط أن نشاهد أبي يموت؟
Mom. Why must you compete with us?
أم.  لماذا يجب أن تنافسنا؟
I don't want to compete with you.
لا أريد أن أتنافس معك.
I just want to tell you this.
أنا فقط أريد أن أخبرك بهذا.
If you insist on inserting a nasogastric tube in him,
إذا كنت تصر على إدخال أنبوب أنفي معدي فيه ،
I'm also going to tell the press and do interviews.
سأخبر الصحافة أيضًا وأجري مقابلات.
As long as I'm alive,
طالما أنا على قيد الحياة ،
I won't allow you guys to do this.
لن أسمح لكم يا رفاق بالقيام بذلك.
Do you really have to do this?
هل حقا يجب أن تفعل هذا؟
Yes.
نعم.
I wonder how their discussion is going.
أتساءل كيف تجري مناقشاتهم.
I can't stand stubborn people...
لا استطيع تحمل العناد ...
who won't listen to others.
الذين لن يستمعوا للآخرين.
Aren't they tired?
أليسوا متعبين؟
Don't say that.
لا تقل ذلك.
You don't know what they've been through.
أنت لا تعرف ما الذي مروا به.
You're judging them with your own moral values.
أنت تحكم عليهم بقيمك الأخلاقية.
Besides, they've been together for 40 years.
علاوة على ذلك ، لقد كانوا معًا لمدة 40 عامًا.
They must really love each other.
يجب أن يحبوا بعضهم البعض حقًا.
Even if they do,
حتى لو كانت تفعل،
this isn't just about the two of them anymore.
لم يعد الأمر يتعلق بالاثنين فقط.
Since they have children,
بما أن لديهم أطفال ،
they should try their best to understand them...
يجب أن يبذلوا قصارى جهدهم لفهمهم ...
and respect the ideas and thoughts of the next generation.
واحترام أفكار وأفكار الجيل القادم.
She told the public about their family matters...
أخبرت الجمهور عن أمور أسرتهم ...
just because she is at odds with her children.
لمجرد أنها على خلاف مع أطفالها.
This kind of love is too selfish.
هذا النوع من الحب أناني للغاية.
What is it?
ما هذا؟
I think you're really cute.
أعتقد أنك لطيف حقًا.
How's my dad?
كيف حال ابي
It's acute heart failure.
إنه قصور حاد في القلب.
He's being resuscitated now.
يتم إنعاشه الآن.
Dr. Xiao.
دكتور شياو.
The patient's condition is stable now.
حالة المريض مستقرة الآن.
Have you decided?
هل قررت؟
Mom.
أم.
Are you just going to watch Dad die?
هل ستشاهد أبي يموت؟
- Mom, say something. - Mom.
- أمي ، قولي شيئًا.  - أم.
Mom, can you bear to see him leave? Mom.
أمي ، هل يمكنك أن تتحمل رؤيته يغادر؟  أم.
Insert the tube in for him.
أدخل الأنبوب من أجله.
Insert the nasogastric tube.
أدخل الأنبوب الأنفي المعدي.
I'd like to be alone with him for a while.
أود أن أكون وحدي معه لفترة من الوقت.
Is that okay?
هل هذا مقبول؟
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
A year ago,
قبل عام،
when I held your hand like this,
عندما أمسك بيدك هكذا ،
you could respond to me.
يمكنك الرد علي.
I won't be able to get a response like that anymore.
لن أتمكن من الحصول على رد مثل هذا بعد الآن.
The hardest thing to face in life is death.
أصعب شيء تواجهه في الحياة هو الموت.
I can't believe your life and death...
لا أصدق حياتك وموتك ...
keep tearing my heart apart...
استمر في تمزيق قلبي ...
time and time again.
مرارا وتكرارا.
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف.
I tried one last time but failed again.
حاولت مرة أخيرة لكنني فشلت مرة أخرى.
I can't do anything else for you anymore.
لا يمكنني فعل أي شيء آخر من أجلك بعد الآن.
I can't cry or call out for you.
لا أستطيع البكاء أو الصراخ من أجلك.
I hope it's like the doctor said.
آمل أن يكون الأمر كما قال الطبيب.
You don't have me in your heart anymore.
ليس لديكني في قلبك بعد الآن.
But you...
لكنك...
will live in my heart forever.
سأعيش في قلبي إلى الأبد.
Goodbye, Shi Lei.
وداعا ، شي لي.
Wait for me in the next life.
انتظرني في الحياة القادمة.
- Mom. - Mom.
- أم.  - أم.
These are the daily necessities that Shi Lei needs...
هذه هي الضروريات اليومية التي يحتاجها شي لي ...
and precautions to take note of.
والاحتياطات الواجب مراعاتها.
I'll leave him to you.
سأتركه لك.
Mom.
أم.
All these years,
كل هذه السنوات،
you've always taken care of Dad.
كنت دائما تهتم بأبي.
It has been hard on you.
لقد كان صعبًا عليك.
Xiao Jie and I will take care of him from now on.
شياو جي وأنا سنعتني به من الآن فصاعدًا.
Go home and rest well.
اذهب إلى المنزل واسترح جيدًا.
If anything happens here,
إذا حدث أي شيء هنا ،
I'll tell you right away.
سأخبرك على الفور.
I hope you can take care of Shi Lei the same way I did.
أتمنى أن تعتني بشي لي بنفس الطريقة التي فعلت بها.
Mom.
أم.
Don't worry.
لا تقلق.
Taking care of a patient like this...
رعاية مريض مثل هذا ...
is more difficult than you think.
أصعب مما تعتقد.
It might even break you.
قد يحطمك حتى.
You must take care of yourselves.
يجب أن تعتني بنفسك.
These are sleeping pills.
هذه حبوب منومة.
They'll be of use to you.
ستكون مفيدة لك.
Mom, don't worry.
أمي لا تقلقي.
(Doctor's Office 2)
(مكتب الطبيب 2)
After that long struggle,
بعد ذلك الكفاح الطويل ،
there's finally some peace and quiet.
أخيرًا هناك بعض الهدوء والسكينة.
In a way,
بطريقة،
I think this is a good thing.
انا اعتقد انه شئ جيد.
A good thing?
شيء جيد؟
Think about it.
فكر في الأمر.
This was the patient's family matter.
كانت هذه مسألة عائلة المريض.
Now, because the children's argument with their mom...
الآن ، لأن جدال الأطفال مع أمهم ...
was posted on the Internet,
تم نشره على الإنترنت ،
it became a social topic...
أصبح موضوعًا اجتماعيًا ...
that garnered a lot of attention.
التي حصدت الكثير من الاهتمام.
China is an aging society now,
الصين مجتمع شيخوخة الآن ،
so their medical case...
لذلك حالتهم الطبية ...
is actually very typical.
هو في الواقع نموذجي للغاية.
There are actually a lot of families and patients...
هناك بالفعل الكثير من العائلات والمرضى ...
who face decision dilemmas...
من يواجه معضلات القرار ...
and need society's help and support.
وتحتاج إلى مساعدة المجتمع ودعمه.
There are many discussions based on their case online.
هناك العديد من المناقشات على أساس حالتهم على الإنترنت.
For example, how to take care of Alzheimer's patients...
على سبيل المثال كيف تعتني بمرضى الزهايمر ...
and how to face eventual death.
وكيف نواجه الموت في نهاية المطاف.
So...
لذا...
this chaotic family...
هذه العائلة الفوضوية ...
ended up bringing something positive and valuable.
انتهى الأمر بجلب شيء إيجابي وذا قيمة.
Now that you mention it,
الآن بعد أن ذكرت ذلك ،
it does sound like a good thing.
يبدو أنه شيء جيد.
What are you thinking about?
بم تفكر؟
I heard...
سمعت...
the matter with Lin Ruo Yun and her husband is settled.
تمت تسوية الأمر مع لين رو يون وزوجها.
The family has come to a consensus...
لقد توصلت الأسرة إلى توافق ...
and agreed to nasogastric intubation.
ووافقت على التنبيب الأنفي المعدي.
Speaking of which,
بالحديث عن هذا الموضوع،
if this had happened in the past,
إذا حدث هذا في الماضي ،
I would've fought until the end with the children.
كنت سأقاتل حتى النهاية مع الأطفال.
I told you.
أخبرتك.
I've been unknowingly brainwashed by you.
لقد تم غسل دماغي من قبلك دون علمي.
Living in pain is still better than death.
العيش في الألم لا يزال أفضل من الموت.
That's how a lot of people think.
هذا ما يعتقده الكثير من الناس.
But there's also a small group of people...
ولكن هناك أيضًا مجموعة صغيرة من الأشخاص ...
who are like Lin Ruo Yun.
من هم مثل لين رو يون.
They choose to face reality.
اختاروا مواجهة الواقع.
There's no right or wrong when it comes to these things.
ليس هناك صواب أو خطأ عندما يتعلق الأمر بهذه الأشياء.
Look.
نظرة.
These are the comments on her Weibo.
هذه هي التعليقات على موقعها Weibo.
So many people are arguing,
الكثير من الناس يتجادلون ،
but there's no result.
لكن لا توجد نتيجة.
So just let it go.
لذا فقط دعها تذهب
Tang Hua's mom arranged a lot of blind dates for her?
رتبت والدة تانغ هوا الكثير من المواعيد العمياء لها؟
Two of them even ran into each other.
حتى أن اثنين منهم اصطدموا ببعضهم البعض.
It was quite awkward.
كان محرجا جدا.
No matter how anxious Mrs. Tang is,
بغض النظر عن مدى قلق السيدة تانغ ،
she can't do this.
هي لا تستطيع فعل هذا.
I guess Mrs. Tang is so anxious that she doesn't care anymore.
أعتقد أن السيدة تانغ قلقة للغاية لدرجة أنها لم تعد تهتم.
But from what I see,
لكن مما أراه ،
Mrs. Tang won't stop.
السيدة تانغ لن تتوقف.
Who knows what other trouble there will be?
من يدري ما هي المشاكل الأخرى التي ستكون هناك؟
You're purposely sending these people to disgust me, right?
أنت ترسل هؤلاء الناس عن قصد ليثيرون اشمئزازي ، أليس كذلك؟
If they keep coming to mess around,
إذا استمروا في القدوم للعبث ،
I'm cutting ties with you.
أنا أقطع العلاقات معك.
Tang Hua.
تانغ هوا.
Stop showing up in front of me.
توقف عن الظهور أمامي.
I'm annoyed right now.
أنا منزعج الآن.
I know you're annoyed.
أعلم أنك منزعج.
I have a way to free you of your troubles.
لدي طريقة لتحريرك من مشاكلك.
You have a way?
لديك طريق؟
What can you do?
ما الذي تستطيع القيام به؟
The reason Mrs. Tang is doing so much...
سبب قيام السيدة تانغ بالكثير ...
is actually quite simple.
هو في الواقع بسيط للغاية.
She just wants you to find a boyfriend as soon as possible.
إنها تريدك فقط أن تجد صديقها في أسرع وقت ممكن.
If you fulfill her wish,
إذا كنت تحقق رغبتها ،
then she'll stop.
ثم ستتوقف.
I knew I couldn't count on you.
كنت أعرف أنني لا أستطيع الاعتماد عليك.
If I had a boyfriend,
إذا كان لدي صديق ،
would I be so troubled?
هل سأكون مضطرب جدا؟
What I mean is...
ما أعنيه هو...
you can get a fake boyfriend.
يمكنك الحصول على صديق مزيف.
Get a fake boyfriend?
الحصول على صديق مزيف؟
Get lost.
اغرب عن وجهي.
I was in a drama club when I was in college.
كنت في نادي الدراما عندما كنت في الكلية.
My acting is not bad.
تمثيلي ليس سيئا.
If I got a boyfriend like you,
إذا كان لدي صديق مثلك ،
my mom would jump in a river.
أمي تقفز في النهر.
What's the matter?
ما الأمر؟
Why do you look so glum?
لماذا تبدو كئيبا جدا؟
You haven't been yourself all morning.
لم تكن على طبيعتك طوال الصباح.
Last night,
ليلة أمس،
my mom talked to me for half the night.
أمي تحدثت معي لمدة نصف الليل.
I was in a daze the whole day.
كنت في حالة ذهول طوال اليوم.
I almost made a huge mistake.
كدت أرتكب خطأ فادحًا.
If she continues this,
إذا واصلت هذا ،
I really don't know what to do.
أنا حقا لا أعرف ما يجب القيام به.
That can't be.
لا يمكن أن يكون.
I think Mrs. Tang will only do this once in a while.
أعتقد أن السيدة تانغ ستفعل ذلك مرة واحدة كل فترة.
She's getting on in years.
انها تتقدم في السنوات.
If she doesn't get any sleep at night every day,
إذا لم تنام في الليل كل يوم ،
she won't be able to handle it.
لن تكون قادرة على التعامل معها.
Don't underestimate my mom.
لا تقلل من شأن أمي.
My mom was a night owl when she was young.
كانت أمي بومة ليلية عندما كانت صغيرة.
She's retired now.
لقد تقاعدت الآن.
She has plenty of time to catch up on sleep during the day.
لديها متسع من الوقت لتعويض النوم أثناء النهار.
She's prepared for a long-term battle with me.
إنها مستعدة لخوض معركة طويلة الأمد معي.
If this goes on, I'll go crazy first.
إذا استمر هذا ، سأصاب بالجنون أولاً.
Then why don't you consider Chen Zhi's suggestion?
إذن لماذا لا تفكر في اقتراح تشين تشي؟
In his dreams.
في أحلامه.
I didn't say you have to find Chen Zhi.
لم أقل إنك يجب أن تجد Chen Zhi.
He's not the only guy in our department.
إنه ليس الرجل الوحيد في قسمنا.
Then who do you think...
ثم من تعتقد ...
is suitable for me?
هل يناسبني؟
What are you two talking about, pretty ladies?
ما الذي تتحدثان عنه أيها السيدات الجميلات؟
Why are you so mysterious?
لماذا أنت غامض جدا؟
Dr. Xu.
دكتور شو.
You've been working too hard these days.
لقد كنت تعمل بجد هذه الأيام.
Have some cola to perk yourself up.
احصل على بعض الكولا لتنشيط نفسك.
Most importantly,
الاكثر اهمية،
we need your help.
نحن نحتاج مساعدتك.
Of course.
بالطبع.
Tell me.
أخبرني.
What needs to be moved in the department this time?
ما الذي يجب نقله في القسم هذه المرة؟
Xu Yi Ran,
شو يي ران ،
I want you to be my boyfriend.
أريد منك أن تكون صديقي.
This sip really woke me up.
هذه الرشفة أيقظتني حقًا.
Really?
هل حقا؟
No.
رقم.
I mean, my fake boyfriend.
أعني ، صديقي المزيف.
Did you have to react like that?
هل كان عليك أن تتصرف هكذا؟
I feel very sorry for your situation,
أشعر بالأسف الشديد لموقفك ،
but I'm afraid I can't help you.
لكنني أخشى أنني لا أستطيع مساعدتك.
Dr. Xu, why are you being like this?
دكتور شو ، لماذا أنت هكذا؟
I even helped you when you asked me...
لقد ساعدتك حتى عندما سألتني ...
to pretend to be your fiancée.
لتتظاهر بأنها خطيبتك.
That's exactly the point.
هذا بالضبط هو الهدف.
Think about it.
فكر في الأمر.
Just a few days ago,
قبل أيام قليلة فقط ،
I put on an act in front of Mrs. Tang...
قمت بعمل أمام السيدة تانغ ...
and told her Lin Zhi was my fiancée.
وأخبرتها أن لين تشي كانت خطيبتي.
But just a few days later,
ولكن بعد أيام قليلة ،
I've become Tang Hua's boyfriend.
لقد أصبحت صديق تانغ هوا.
Mrs. Tang would kick me out right away.
السيدة تانغ ستطردني على الفور.
How could I forget that?
كيف يمكنني أن أنسى ذلك؟
You can't fool her forever.
لا يمكنك خداعها إلى الأبد.
I suggest you just find a real one.
أقترح عليك فقط العثور على واحدة حقيقية.
It might even be easier than finding a fake one.
قد يكون الأمر أسهل من العثور على واحدة مزيفة.
I don't care about "forever" right now.
لا يهمني "إلى الأبد" الآن.
I just care about this moment now.
أنا فقط أهتم بهذه اللحظة الآن.
Actually, if you have to find a fake one,
في الواقع ، إذا كان عليك العثور على واحدة مزيفة ،
it's not like there isn't a suitable candidate.
ليس الأمر وكأنه لا يوجد مرشح مناسب.
Are you talking about Chen Zhi?
هل تتحدث عن Chen Zhi؟
I wouldn't ask him even if it's just a fake boyfriend.
لن أسأله حتى لو كان مجرد صديق مزيف.
I'm annoyed every time I see him.
أنا منزعج في كل مرة أراه.
You may be annoyed,
قد تكون منزعج ،
but first, Chen Zhi will definitely be willing to help you.
لكن أولاً ، سيكون Chen Zhi بالتأكيد على استعداد لمساعدتك.
He'll listen to everything you say.
سوف يستمع إلى كل ما تقوله.
I still won't choose him.
ما زلت لن أختاره.
Then you can only choose...
ثم يمكنك فقط اختيار ...
between Mom Lu and Bai Zhu.
بين أمي لو وباي تشو.
Just kill me.
فقط اقتلني.
I can't help you.
لا استطيع مساعدتك.
Chen Zhi.
تشن تشي.
I'll give you a chance.
سأعطيك فرصة.
Be my fake boyfriend.
كن صديقي المزيف.